<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/tag/review/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-06-13T10:40:31+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/tag/review/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Tech Oasis | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Tech Oasis</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">RX 5600 XT Review</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/5600xt" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RX 5600 XT Review" />
      <published>2020-04-29T11:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-29T11:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/5600xt</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/5600xt">&lt;p&gt;This is AMD’s answer to the mid range graphics card market. Can the RX 5600 XT compete with Nvidia’s 1660 Super and 1660 Ti?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;amd-radeon-5600-xt&quot;&gt;AMD Radeon 5600 XT&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming out on the 21st Jan 2020, the Radeon 5600 series was AMD’s answer to Nvidia’s domination in the £200 to £280 graphics card market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/5600xt/5600sapphire.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Radeon RX 5600XT&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pricing&quot;&gt;Pricing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5600 XT at first confused enthusiasts as they thought it was supposed to compete with the £250 Nvidia GeForce 1660 Ti. However AMD opted to price it around £30 more, coming in on average at £280. 
In response to this Nvidia dropped the price of their RTX 2060 down to £300, in the form of the EVGA “KO” variant. However, the AMD card still trades blows with Nvidia’s more expensive card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;performance&quot;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5600 XT is a brilliant performer. This card could possibly become the king of 1440p gaming. Once thought to be competing with the 1660 Ti, this card blows it out of the water at most titles (admittedly being £30 more expensive). Even the RTX 2060 KO, Nvidia’s response to the card, does not appear to have the upper hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;specs&quot;&gt;Specs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This card is built on AMD’s new RDNA architecture, which is using a 7nm fabrication process. This means better thermals and more efficient power consumption compared to past architectures. 
Other specs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;36 CU (compute units)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clock Speed: 1375MHz base&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Game” clock speed: 1750MHz (this is the speed the GPU can consistently reach while playing games)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comes with 6Gb (a break from the very RAM heavy Polaris cards) of new GDDR6 memory with 192-bit memory bus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Typical power usage is 150-160 watts. AMD recommends at least a 450w PSU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These parts come together to make a brilliant card for the price. Beating the 2060 in most games, all while consuming less power. This card can both game in the 1440p res and 1080p, but you are pushing it when moving up to 4k. You’ll probably have to turn the settings down a lot. 144hz gaming is also aced by this card, comfortably reaching  144 fps at high settings in games like Apex Legends, Call of Duty, Fortnite, Overwatch, GTA, etc. (when paired with R5 3600). See full list of game FPS according to gpucheck &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gpucheck.com/gpu/amd-radeon-rx-5600-xt/amd-ryzen-5-3600/high#mainads&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;launch-mess&quot;&gt;Launch Mess&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of this card was a bit of a mess. AMD last second released a new VBIOS update which considerably increased performance by upping clock speeds. This meant that not all the cards which were sold did not receive this boost in performance so owners at home had to update it manually, or risk losing performance for their money. 
AMD did this as a response to Nvidia’s 2060 KO, just to make sure it was rendered completely redundant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drivers&quot;&gt;Drivers.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, the 2060 KO was not completely beat because of AMD’s drivers, letting them down, &lt;strong&gt;again&lt;/strong&gt;. This card is definitely not void of some stability problems. I have experienced multiple crashes and strange behaviour, even after Radeon 20.02.2 driver up date supposedly fixed these issues. Still to this day AMD still has a huge driver quality problem that is becoming more and more painful.  And still Nvidia offer quality, stable drivers. This is a big selling point of the KO over the 5600.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overall&quot;&gt;Overall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a brilliant card from AMD, coming in and really shaking up the market. It’s price point means it slips inbetween Nvidia’s 1660 Ti and 2060 KO, beating both of them. If you ignore the stability issues, there is no real competition when it comes to performance to the price in this bracket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9 / 10&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Henry Varley</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="our-tech" />
      
        <category term="review" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">This is AMD’s answer to the mid range graphics card market. Can the RX 5600 XT compete with Nvidia’s 1660 Super and 1660 Ti?</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Gabriel’s Gaming Rig</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/gabriels-PC" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gabriel's Gaming Rig" />
      <published>2020-04-29T11:00:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-29T11:00:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/gabriels-PC</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gabriels-PC">&lt;p&gt;This is my gaming rig which I have been using for a couple of months. It has been serving me well, pumping out 240fps, on the games I am currently playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;gabriels-gaming-rig&quot;&gt;Gabriel’s Gaming Rig&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started designing my pc months before I had anywhere near the money that I needed to build it. I was always using pcpartpicker and constantly changing things. My base build was a Ryzen 7 2700X with a GTX 1660 which wasn’t a very smart choice for a gaming build as I wouldn’t be able to utilise all 8 cores. It was especially bad when the price of the Ryzen 5 2600 was so much cheaper while sacrificing very little single-thread performance. Another problem was that I spent too much on the CPU in a gaming build as opposed to the GPU. I am aware that the Ryzen 5 3600 does also seem a bit overkill however the value was/is too good to ignore and was/is still cheaper than the Ryzen 7 2700X.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/gabriels-PC/benchmark.png&quot; alt=&quot;cpu benchmarks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specs&quot;&gt;Specs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CPU: Ryzen 5 3600&lt;br /&gt;
GPU: Vega 56 – Gigabyte OC&lt;br /&gt;
RAM: Corsair vengeance 16gb 3200 MHz&lt;br /&gt;
Motherboard: B450 Aorus elite&lt;br /&gt;
SSD: Sabrent Rocket NVMe PCIe M.2 2280 512gb&lt;br /&gt;
PSU: EVGA 600W 80+&lt;br /&gt;
Case: AeroCool Cylon Mid-Tower RGB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ryzen-5-3600&quot;&gt;Ryzen 5 3600&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/gabriels-PC/ryzen_3600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ryzen 3600 is an amazing CPU for the price having 6 cores and 12 threads with a base clock of 3.6GHz and a turbo boost of up to 4.2GHz. Is has 32mb of cache which is great for gaming. I chose the Ryzen 5 3600 because it’s immense value is almost incomparable with any CPU in the same price range. Its single-threaded performance is very good making it great for me as I am primarily using it for gaming. However, it is still a Hexa-core processor meaning it is still strong in other areas such as editing, which I also do on occasion. So far it has served me well. however, I have had a few minor setbacks with it. The processor I received does not reach the advertised turbo boost maxing out at 4.08GHz. When overclocking to over 4.1GHz I get stuck in a boot loop. I have tried some fixes such as flashing the motherboard bios. Unfortunately, I have gotten little success. One thing I am yet to try is reinstalling the chipset drivers. If that works I will update this post. Minus the issues my overall experience has been good and would recommend it to anyone building a midrange custom PC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vega-56&quot;&gt;Vega 56&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/gabriels-PC/vega_56.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;vega 56&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vega 56 is a great card for being released in 2017. I bought a refurbished Gigabyte OC version which comes with 3 display ports and 3 HDMI ports. It is manually overclocked to 1501MHz clock speed and 800Mhz memory clock. It comes with 8GB of VRAM which is more than enough for any modern title. Paired with my CPU it pumps out 240fps in games such as Overwatch, Fortnite, Apex Legends and Destiny 2 in 1080p. Although this means I have to play at low settings to achieve this I value hitting 240fps and getting full value out of my 240hz monitor over the game looking better. However, this does not mean that it is not capable of running 60fps on max settings if you prefer that. The card does get quite hot and draws a lot of power getting up to 75°C+ when overclocking. The power consumption can be an issue as spikes in power can cause the pc to crash. To avoid this make sure you use two separate 8 pin connectors to power the GPU. This will require at least a semi-modular power supply. The card can also get quite loud when running full wack so if you do not want a loud card either make sure you have some seriously good airflow or refrain from buying this card. Other than the crashes my experience with the Vega 56 has been very positive especially with it being a 2017 card. I would no longer recommend this card as the 5600XT is a similar price if not cheaper and will offer more value. It is also quieter, cooler with less power consumption making the Vega 56 redundant (which it should).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;corsair-vengeance-16gb-3200mhz&quot;&gt;Corsair vengeance 16gb 3200MHz&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets\images\gabriels-PC\corsair_vengeance.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;corsair ram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was designing my rig I knew that 16gb of RAM was the amount I needed. As they say, 8 is good but 16 is ideal. I also knew that Ryzen CPUs benefited from higher memory speeds. This is why I chose 3200MHz as it is generally accepted as the “sweet spot” when it comes to price to performance. Looking back I probably have gone for 3000MHz if it had been £10 cheaper as RAM is so easy to overclock. I got 2 sticks of 8 (of course) for that extra dual-channel performance so I can get a few extra frames. When I bought them RAM prices were extremely low – and still are – which was great and I was very pleased with it. Overall experience has been great with 0 issues as of so far including my overclocking. I am currently running them at 3600MHz which is always a nice extra. I would highly recommend this RAM to anyone doing a mid-range to low high-end build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;b450-aorus-elite&quot;&gt;B450 Aorus elite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/gabriels-PC/aorus_elite.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;b450 mdb&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it came to a motherboard I did not want to spend a large of sum money but I did want it to be fairly upgrade friendly. Luckily for me, I had chosen a AMD CPU meaning that I would not need to spend as much on a board. I decided upon a B450 as I knew that an X570 or X470 would be more expensive and I was not planning on doing a huge amount of overclocking or extreme overclocking. When it came to board features I knew that I wanted; 4 RAM slots, 2 NVME m.2 slots, and some decent IO. Taking all the factors stated above into account a settled on the B450 Aorus elite. It comes with all the things that I wanted including some RGB which we all know drastically increases gaming performance. It was originally £20 more than I was willing to spend but ended up being on a discount which meant that I bought it. The motherboard is very good and fitted my needs perfectly. It was very nice that the IO shield was pre-installed as saved some hassle. It had a generous amount of USB ports which is great for me as I end up using many of them. The audio jacks were a bit overkill for me, that being an understatement, but it was a bonus. Would recommend this to anyone that wants a board that can have an upgrade or two but does not break the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sabrent-rocket-nvme-pcie-m2-2280-512gb&quot;&gt;Sabrent Rocket NVMe PCIe M.2 2280 512gb&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/gabriels-PC/sabrent_rocket.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sabrent rocket&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was choosing and SSD I wanted something fast and was willing to compromise some storage for a faster one. I originally was going to get a Western Digital blue 500gb as it was decently fast and still an NVMe drive. I ordered it and just before it arrived Henry found a much faster SSD for the same price with brilliant reviews on Amazon. It was the Sabrent rocket NVMe SSD. I ended up cancelling my order and buying the rocket instead. I am very pleased that I made this decision as my games load incredibly fast and the very small amount of extra storage is a small freebie. I also can’t let henry have a better one than me. Extremely pleased with this SSD as it hits all the advertised speeds if not higher and I have had zero issues. I would highly recommend it to anyone that has an m.2 slot which supports an NVMe drive. If you would like to our full review on the Sabrent rocket click &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pklRklhbCjo&amp;amp;t=100s&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;evga-600w-80&quot;&gt;EVGA 600W 80+&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/gabriels-PC/EVGA_PSU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PSU EVGA&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew that I needed a power supply that was at least 550w as the Vega 56 has a high power consumption. I did not want to spend too much on a power supply, as I did not mind having a non-modular power supply, although now that I can not use 2 separate 8 pins I have some regrets. I also wanted to buy from a reliable manufacturer to make sure I still had my parts in 3 months. I ended up going for an EVGA 600w for all the reasons stated above. It is rated 80+ bronze which is always nice. Unfortunately it ended up failing halfway through gaming sessions and eventually did not start at all. luckily Amazon has amazing customer service and I was able to receive a full refund. I bought a 550W Corsair which is now in the build at my mums house. I now have a 650W Corsair in this build. A good PSU for a good price, I was just unlucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aerocool-cylon-mid-tower-rgb&quot;&gt;AeroCool Cylon Mid-Tower RGB&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/gabriels-PC/aerocool_cylon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;case Aerocool cylon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my case, I decided to go cheap. I did not mind cable managing in a rough environment if it meant It gave me more budget towards other parts of the build. The only thing that was a must-have was a power supply shroud that I could shove all my spare cables into. So I decided to choose the AeroCool Cylon. The case is good for the price but the airflow is pretty bad. It has a tempered glass panel which was something that I wanted so I could see into my pc and see the RGB. The case also has an/ RGB strip that is changed by a button on the front but is not very customisable. It has one USB 3.0 and 2 USB 2.0 ports. It also has a micro SD reader which could possibly be useful. It is a pretty decent case that I would recommend if you are okay with bad airflow and difficult cable management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I am very happy with my build and had a lot of fun building it. I think that mostly made the correct decisions and think that it turned out great. Gaming has never been more fun and it is nice to be part of the PC master race.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Gabriel Nilsson</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="our-tech" />
      
        <category term="review" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">This is my gaming rig which I have been using for a couple of months. It has been serving me well, pumping out 240fps, on the games I am currently playing.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Moto G7 Power</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/moto-g7-power" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moto G7 Power" />
      <published>2020-04-19T11:18:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-19T11:18:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/moto-g7-power</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/moto-g7-power">&lt;p&gt;When it comes to cheap, low end phones, Motorola get it right time and time again. Hey guys its tech oasis and this is the Moto G7 Power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;build&quot;&gt;Build&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The build feels nice, with polymer glass on the back. It has some weight to it and feels like a quality device. Unfortunately, there is no form of water resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power and volume buttons are in acceptable positions, along the right side of the phone. The volume rocker could be a bit lower down though for people with smaller hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;options&quot;&gt;Options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get this phone in 3 colours; Black, Blue and a very snazzy Violet colour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finger-print-sensor&quot;&gt;Finger print sensor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Moto G7 Power has a great little finger print sensor that is lightning fast and only takes a couple of hours to get used to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;battery&quot;&gt;Battery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stand out feature of this phone is the huge 5000 mAh battery. I’ve been using this phone for a couple of months now and the phone can comfortably last me 3 days under moderate usage. So, if you’re someone who forgets to charge, or if you have a weekend away, this phone is for you. When it does finally run out however, you can charge it up very quickly with Motorola’s TurboPower charging technology. The phone has a USB-C port at the bottom. No wireless charging here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;display&quot;&gt;Display&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has a 6.2” LCD Gorilla Glass display with a resolution of 1520 by 720. The screen is fine but not outstanding, especially when compared to a higher end OLED screen. It’s mostly bezelless having a thicker chin showing some Motorola branding at the bottom. Also don’t forget about the medium size notch at the top of the display. The screen gets quite bright but you might find it hard to see things in direct sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/motog7/phone4.jpg#full&quot; alt=&quot;The Phone is lit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;camera&quot;&gt;Camera&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the back of the phone you’ll find a single 12 MP camera that can shoot up to 4k video (30fps).  It’s decent but is definitely a point that could be improved. The camera on the front is 8 MP and is fine for video calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;speaker&quot;&gt;Speaker&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speaker is on the front next to the camera and will do for most uses but can be a bit tinny and could be higher quality. And of course, thank god, a 3.5mm headphone jack is still present on this phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;software&quot;&gt;Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the software side of things, the moto G7 Power comes with almost pure stock android 9 along with some features Motorola have thrown in there. For example, the very useful camera and torch gestures. Other things include the always on screen, great for quickly checking the time and notifications, without needing to find the power button. Also Motorola have added a surprisingly good facial recognition feature that sometimes works too well. I turned it off because I want to look at notifications without unlocking my phone every time I pick it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;inside&quot;&gt;Inside&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model here has 4 GB of memory, giving the user a smooth multi-tasking experience. 64 GB of storage is a generous amount and if you find yourself running out, you can always expand with up to a 512 GB micro SD card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for speed, there’s absolutely no problem. It has an octa core Qualcomm® Snapdragon™ 632 that runs at 1.8 gHz. This makes for a nice snappy experience that can run pretty much any app smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/motog7/phone2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Phone is lit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extras&quot;&gt;Extras!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sweet surprise for a budget phone is the included transparent case it comes with. It can do an okay job protecting your phone but doesn’t look too good and can become grimy easily. I would still consider getting a better case if you drop your phone a lot. Very nice gesture from Motorola. Further reasons to get a case is that this phone is a HUGE fingerprint magnet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall this is another outstanding budget phone from Motorola’s G line up. And, with a £180 price tag, this could possibly be the king of sub £200 phones.  We are excited to see if Motorola can continue delivering such value phones generation after generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9 / 10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go check out our video review of this phone on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCmbieU3y9vDvt7F0nrZxGWQ&quot;&gt;Tech Oasis youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Henry Varley</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="our-tech" />
      
        <category term="review" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">When it comes to cheap, low end phones, Motorola get it right time and time again. Hey guys its tech oasis and this is the Moto G7 Power.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Henry’s Laptop</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/lenovo-laptop" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Henry's Laptop" />
      <published>2020-04-18T14:18:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-18T14:18:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/lenovo-laptop</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lenovo-laptop">&lt;h1 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first laptop. I got it for my 14th birthday after getting a load of money. I got it from Curry’s PC world for £550, £50 off because of a deal involving Ryzen based computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before that I had been scouring the internet for countless hours to find my perfect laptop. I had a little over £500 to spend, a good amount for a longlasting, reliable laptop. At first I tried my luck at an incredible deal - an Acer Nitro laptop (I forgot the exact one) for around £200 under usual price, bringing it to £500. It was from a 3rd party vendor and we were half expecting something to be dodgy about it…  And that was exactly what we got. A painful week after ordering, I got an email from Amazon saying the seller no longer “had” the laptop and it was not coming. A full refund was given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that whole thing, we decided to get a laptop from a respectable seller. My Dad and I found the Lenovo IdeaPad series and thought it looked good. Initially we were going for the 15” 530S and sent an order to pick it up in the shop. However, just after we sent the order, to my dismay and Dad’s annoyance, I noticed that the 15” had a miserable battery life of 3 hours. The 14” model however had a considerably better 6 hours of power. So, when we got to the shop I asked if there was any chance we could have it swapped for the 14 inch model. Luckily, they had a single model stocked in the shop and they let us swap it out. It was £50 more however, money that I didn’t have at the time. I told my Dad I would  pay it back to him later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked out of PC world holding my laptop and protecting it with my life. This was the most expensive thing I had ever bought, by &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;teething-problems&quot;&gt;Teething problems&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was super happy with my Lenovo IdeaPad 530S 14” and loved how thin it was. I didn’t even realise when looking online! Thickness wasn’t really a priority for me but I was surprised with how much I liked it, especially as it competed with the thickness of &lt;a href=&quot;macbook-air.html&quot;&gt;Gabriel’s MacBook Air&lt;/a&gt;. However, there were some very bad early problems with the laptop. On one of the first time I was using it, as I watched a YouTube video, I got a dreaded blue screen of death. The error code was: VIDEO SCHEDULER INTERNAL ERROR. It seemed to be something to do with the graphics drivers - happening almost exclusively when watching videos. I tried updating the drivers and my dad got in conversation with Microsoft. Our efforts to fix the problem were fruitless, and, we were on the brink of sending it back to Curry’s saying it was faulty. This was about the time were the problems started to mysteriously fade away. At the time of writing, I hadn’t experienced a critical error for many months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second annoying problem that was more infuriating than the last was the complete stoppage of all sound coming out off the speakers. This was an very annoying issue that I spent ages trying to fix. Again there seemed to be an issue with the Realtek drivers after there was an update. My Dad and I had no idea how to fix this and everything we tried did nothing. Unfortunately we had to resort to the ultimate failsafe to fix the problem, a full Windows restart. ):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully I have a tech savvy house to fix these issues however a regular person would probably have to send it back if they experienced these problems. Of course, these problems won’t effect every one of these laptops and it’s just a one off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;overall-experience&quot;&gt;Overall Experience&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;build&quot;&gt;Build&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This a brilliant laptop from Lenovo. The build quality is utterly amazing for the price with a fully aluminium body apart from some plastic bordering the screen. The hinge is sturdy and goes back to a 180 degree angle. Bezels are on the minimum, around a centimetre with a thicker chin on the bottom for some Lenovo branding. Like I said, this laptop is super thin, under 1.65cm when closed. That’s just 1mm thicker than the latest MacBook Air (at its thickest point).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;speakers&quot;&gt;Speakers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speakers are not special, two on the bottom at the sides. They can get a bit muffled if covered by some kind of fabric, not good if you’re using it to watch Netflix on your bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trackpad&quot;&gt;Trackpad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trackpad is great on this laptop. Really easy to use, nice size and feel, made of glass. It handles gestures very well, running its Windows Precision drivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keyboard&quot;&gt;Keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keyboard might be an issue for some. It is mushy with very low clickyness with each keystroke. It could definitely be improved. The layout is fine but I wish the # key was not put so close to the enter key as it sometimes leads to me accidentally pressing it. Also I think they could of made the up and down arrow keys bigger and gotten rid of some of the size off the right shift, I literally never use right shift anyway. Don’t forget that this keyboard also comes with two levels of brightness for its back lighting, just click Fn+Space to cycle between them. There are also some shortcut keys incorporated into the function keys, these include brightness, sound and aeroplane mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;display&quot;&gt;Display&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The display has its pros and cons. Pros are that it’s a nice full HD display. Also an absolute win for this laptop is that the display is IPS. This makes the colours look soooo much better than a TN panel and is an absolute must for any laptop. Of course the display runs at 60Hz and don’t expect to be getting professional gamer grade response times from it either. One problem I find with the display is it doesn’t go very bright. This has been a problem for me when I have wanted do do coding outside or near a window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;io&quot;&gt;IO&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully this laptop has a healthy selection of good IO. On the left side there is the power adaptor, full size HDMI, a USB A port, USB C port (not Thunderbolt 3) and finally a headphone jack. As for the right side, there is another USB type A and a full size SD card reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;battery&quot;&gt;Battery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know how I said I swapped the laptop out for this one to get better battery life? Well, this laptop has about the same as it said the other model had, which is, not a lot. You can not get much life out of this laptop at all and it will only last you about 3 - 4 hours use. ):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fans&quot;&gt;Fans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a single fan on the left side of the device sucking air in from the bottom. It gets moderately loud under heavy load and should be is easily bearable for short amounts of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;on-the-inside&quot;&gt;On the inside&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specs are great on this device. I got it with a Ryzen 2500U with Vega 8 Mobile graphics. Paired with that, 8 GB of 2400mHz RAM and a snappy 256 GB M.2 SSD. These components overall lead a very fast computer for normal use. It breezes through multi-tasking easily with its 8-threaded CPU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, thanks to the Vega 8 graphics, you will be able to do some casual gaming, running League of Legends at nice frame rates and can run Fortnite if you crank down the settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally don’t expect to be doing any super intensive stuff like editing large videos or rendering on this laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/lenovolaptop/hinge.jpg#full&quot; alt=&quot;It's thin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall this laptop has served me very well and has not shown signs of slowing. It aces everything a casual user might need and has the speed to match. I think this Laptop would be perfect for anyone who needs a general purpose portable computer - without breaking the bank.
The problems I had with it at first were annoying, but I could have always gone and swapped it for another one that didn’t have the faults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 / 10&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Henry Varley</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="our-tech" />
      
        <category term="review" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Review</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Gabriel’s Macbook Air</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/macbook-air" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gabriel's Macbook Air" />
      <published>2020-04-18T13:18:00+01:00</published>
      <updated>2020-04-18T13:18:00+01:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/macbook-air</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/macbook-air">&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-mac&quot;&gt;Why mac?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people who know more about computers and hardware than the average person, Apple products are usually not a popular choice. They are seen as expensive and low value. So why did I choose to get a MacBook air? Ecosystem: At the time I had an iphone and used my iPad on a daily basis and having a MacBook would connect all these devices and make everything much easier. Both my parents also had MacBooks so it be easier there as well. MacOS: I personally find MacOS much more appealing than windows and felt that the extra money spent would be towards getting it. When you buy a Mac you do pay extra but you pay that money so that apple doesn’t have to put ads and other ways of making money in the OS. I also had quite a bad experience with Windows 7 that made we lean towards MacOS. Quality guarantee: Since both my parents had MacBooks I knew exactly what I was getting. No need to go through endless reviews on the laptop. You save yourself a lot of time! All of these things led me to buying a MacBook. Now I have an Android phone, which you can see here, and I rarely use my iPad anymore. I’m also completely fine with windows 10 (and 7 for that matter) but I still do prefer MacOS. If I were to buy a laptop now I would probably go with a windows one as it would save me some money. If Linux was more widely used and supported, and I could save some money on my laptop, I would use that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/macbook_air/macbook6.jpg#full&quot; alt=&quot;The Mac&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;build&quot;&gt;Build&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected from a MacBook the build is very sturdy but at the same time very light. It feels very sturdy despite it’s sleekness and is easy to hold. It is an older model so the bezels are quite big and don’t look to good, especially when compared to more modern laptops. The hinge is very smooth so the laptop can be opened with one finger. The classic apple design is very aesthetically pleasing to look at and looks good in most setups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;speakers&quot;&gt;Speakers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speakers are okay, nothing fantastic but will do for most basic uses. They are located along the left and right side of the keyboard so don’t worry about them being blocked easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trackpad&quot;&gt;Trackpad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again as expected from a MacBook, the trackpad is excellent! It is very responsive and the gestures save you a lot of time when using the laptop. It’s very nice not needing to plug in a mouse because the trackpad is barely usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keyboard&quot;&gt;Keyboard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyboard is very responsive, and since it is an older model they are not butterfly keys which I am personally not a big fan of. The backlighting fits with Macs design and is enough to help you see the keys in the dark but not blind you. Some of the keys can be quite small and close and make it harder when trying to touch type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;display&quot;&gt;Display&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resolution is not full HD being 1440x900. This is obviously a bit disappointing as you would always hope to get at least 1080p. It’s still nice and clear however and for everything the average user does it is great. It has a TN panel, meaning it has not got the best viewing angles but it’s still pretty good. The display is 13 inches which I find is a good size for everything I want to do. It is 60hz and it gets quite bright but can be difficult in strong sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;io&quot;&gt;IO&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being and older laptop it does not have the most up to date IO. It has 2 USB 3.0 ports (one on each side) which is enough especially since the trackpad is good so a mouse is not needed. It unfortunately has no USB type C ports. It also has a thunderbolt 2 port if you want to connect a monitor to it. It has a MagSafe 2 power port, which is a very nice quality of life feature. Finally it has a SDXC card slot which can also be useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;battery&quot;&gt;Battery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battery life on this laptop is really where is shines. It has a 54 watt battery which isn’t the biggest battery in the word. However since the display isn’t the newest the display does not drain the battery meaning that it has a battery life of around 6-8 hours which is pretty incredible. This is perfect for people who travel or commute a lot and need to get things done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fans&quot;&gt;Fans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fans are located at the back near the hinge and do a decent job cooling your computer when doing simple tasks. When you do some more intensive stuff however, that’s when things get loud. The noise is beatable for a bit but they really are loud and can be annoying as anything slightly intensive gets them going full wack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;storage&quot;&gt;Storage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has 128GB of PCIe-based SSD. It’s not a very impressive amount of storage considering it’s a laptop but it can do for some people. It’s pretty fast since it’s an SSD which is always nice. If you want more then you’ll have to select the 256GB model when purchasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;main-components&quot;&gt;Main components&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My model has a dual Core i5 5350U 1.8GHz that can turbo boost up to 2.9GHz. It’s pretty decent and runs all your basic tasks smoothly. It has 8GB of 1600MHz LPDDR3 which is enough but don’t expect to do intensive full HD editing. It has Intel HD graphics 6000 which is fine and can do some casual gaming such as League of Legends and Minecraft. You won’t be running any shadow of the tomb raider here! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/macbook_air/macbook7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pic of Mac&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the model is pretty good. However it’s pretty old so you aren’t getting a lot of the newer tech and it’s still pretty expensive. I would recommend this laptop to anyone who is looking for a Mac but maybe not if they were just looking for a laptop. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6.5/10&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Gabriel Nilsson</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="our-tech" />
      
        <category term="review" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Why mac?</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
